{"tossups": [{"question": "<b>The short silent film</b><em><b> The Last Cartridges</b></em><b> depicts an incident in this battle in which Arsene Lambert\u2019s men defended a retreat from within a house in Bazeilles [bah-zay]. In this battle, Alexandre (+) Ducrot [do-crow] took over command from the injured Marshal MacMahon. Having lost this battle, the Army of Ch\u02c6alons [sha-lone] was prevented from relieving the Siege of (*) </b> Metz and the losing emperor was captured. Helmuth von Moltke led the victorious army in, for the point, what decisive battle in which Napoleon III was captured and his Second French Empire was overthrown?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Sedan</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>From 1927 to 1930, this position was held by Charles Lindbergh\u2019s father-in-law, who had a nickname referring to his frequent breakfast conversations. That man in this post</b> <b>helped draft an agreement in 1929 which allowed (+)</b> <b>Catholic instruction to resume in</b> <b>churches. In this position, Henry Lane Wilson was accused of supporting the events of the Ten Tragic Days. A man who held this post worked alongside (*)</b> Plutarco Calles, while another may have helped arrange the murder of Francisco Madero. For the point, name this position in which Dwight Morrow tried to mediate the Cristero War on behalf of Calvin Coolidge.", "answer": "<b> U.S. Ambassador to Mexico</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One of these events organized by John Philip Kemble sparked the Old Price Riot. These events could be restricted by the government under Robert Walpole\u2019s 1737 Licensing Act.</b> <b>Peg Woffington, David (+)</b> <b>Garrick, and Sarah Siddons were known for participating in</b> <b>these events on Drury Lane. A building in Blackfriars was used for these events by the Lord (*)</b> Chamberlain\u2019s Men. Scholars debate whether one creator of these things was exposed their mystery and miracle types, which were common in the Middle Ages. For the point, name this sort of event often performed in the Globe Theater.", "answer": "English<b> play</b>s (or<b> theater</b> performances before mentioned; accept Shakespeare\u2019s<b> play</b>s)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "<b>Following this event, the village of Zimoveskaya was renamed. Vasily Kar failed to stop</b> <b>this event in its early stages, while Alexander (+)</b> <b>Bibikov succumbed to cholera while</b> <b>trying to suppress it. During this event, Ivan Mikhelson drove forces out of Kazan shortly after this event\u2019s leader captured it. That was followed by utter defeat at the Battle of (*) </b>Tsaritsyn. The leader of this uprising claimed to be the deceased Peter III and promised to free the serfs. For the point, name this Cossack rebellion during the reign of Catherine the Great.", "answer": "<b> Pugachev\u2019s Rebellion</b> (or<b> Revolt</b>, etc.)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This man suggested that domestic critics of men like Littleton Waller and Jacob Smith should be \u201cdragged out of their homes and lynched.\u201d While trying to stop fires that</b> <b>destroyed the Palace Hotel, this man foolishly ordered the use of (+)</b> <b>dynamite to blow</b> <b>up buildings. Earlier, this man disguised himself as a prisoner alongside Tagalog speaking scouts to capture a (*)</b> rebel leader. For the point, name this American general who declared martial law after the 1906 San Francisco Earthquake but may be best known for capturing Emilio Aguinaldo during the Philippine-American War.", "answer": "Frederick<b> Funston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This location first gained its importance after the Battle of Lake George, and it used to be the site of the Pell family estate. Arthur Saint-Claire was court-martialed for abandoning</b> <b>this location, which is overlooked by Mount (+)</b> <b>Defiance. James Abercromby ordered a</b> <b>disastrous frontal assault on this location, which was then controlled by the French and named Carillon. Its guns were brought by Henry (*)</b> Knox to Massachusetts to end the Siege of Boston. For the point, name this fort in upstate New York that was the target of multiple campaigns in the French and Indian and American Revolutionary Wars.", "answer": "Fort<b> Ticonderoga</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One of this man\u2019s works names a History Channel panel show and is worn as a tattoo by its host, Craig Ferguson. Even though Billy Mays died mid-rap and was replaced by the ShamWow guy, this man lost his Epic Rap Battle of History. Nicolas (+) Cage\u2019s character in the</b><em><b> National Treasure</b></em><b> film series is named for this man, who</b><em><b> Mythbusters</b></em><b> suggests would have suffered a fatal electric shock through the heart had his (*)</b> kite actually been struck by lightning. For the point, name this American founding father who appears on the $100 bill.", "answer": "Benjamin<b> Franklin</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name these two American explorers who both claimed to have reached the North Pole first in the early 1900\u2019s.", "answer": "Robert<b> Peary and</b> Frederick<b> Cook</b> (accept in either order; prompt if only one is given)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man assumed personal control of the army after the success of the enemy side\u2019s Operation Mistral 2. This man went into hiding as an alternative medicine doctor named</b> <b>Dragan Dabic, while he was eventually arrested in (+)</b> <b>Belgrade in 2008. This man was</b> <b>convicted of genocide for his role in the extermination of Muslim men and boys in (*) </b>Srebrenica [sreh-breh-NEET-zah]. For the point, name this former President of Republika Sprska who, in March 2016, was sentenced to 40 years in prison for crimes against humanity committed during the Bosnian War.", "answer": "Radovan<b> Karadzic</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A book titled for this thing claims that barbarian peoples deserve nothing but obedience to \u201can Akbar or a Charlemagne, if they are so fortunate.\u201d In an essay tracing totalitarianism to Rousseau\u2019s support of the (+) \u201cpositive\u201d type of this thing, Oxford scholar Isaiah Berlin distinguished \u201cTwo Concepts of\u201d it. 13 years after</b><em><b> The Road to Serfdom</b></em><b>, Friedrich von Hayek wrote about</b><em><b> The Constitution of</b></em><b> this concept. This thing also titles a book arguing that the (*)</b> \u201charm principle\u201d should be the only restriction on it in civil affairs. For the point, name this absence of repression or restrictions on conduct, a type of political license that titles an 1859 book by John Stuart Mill.", "answer": "<b> liberty</b> (or<b> On Liberty</b>; do not accept \u201cfreedom\u201d or any synonyms)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "At its founding, most of its population was expelled from their home due to Governor (+) Lilburn Boggs\u2019 Executive Order 44. The mayor of this city was killed by a mob while in prison at (*)</b> Carthage after destroying a newspaper for claiming he practiced polygamy. That leader\u2019s successor, Brigham Young, eventually led most of this city\u2019s population west to Utah. For the point, name this city in Illinois founded in 1840 by Joseph Smith as a Mormon utopia.", "answer": "<b> Nauvoo</b>, Illinois (accept<b> Commerce</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Jafar Pishevari led a Soviet-backed breakaway state of this ethnic group. In 2006, riots broke out after a political cartoon depicted a cockroach speaking to a child in the language</b> <b>of this ethnic group. The 366th CIS Regiment helped carry out the (+)</b> <b>Kholjay massacre</b> <b>against this ethnic group. This ethnic group dominates the city of Tabriz and is the largest minority group in Iran. This ethnic group\u2019s primary country fought the (*)</b> Nagorno-Karabakh War with its neighbor, Armenia. For the point, name this Turkic ethnic group in the Caucasus whose members largely live in Baku.", "answer": "<b> Azeri</b>s (or<b> Azerbaijani</b>s)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Journalist Andrew Bolt denied that the people known by this specific term ever existed as part of his country\u2019s \u201cHistory Wars.\u201d In 1981, historian Peter Read coined the term for this subset of people, which inspired the song \u201cThe Dead Heart\u201d by Midnight Oil. The</b> <b>1997 government report (+)</b> <b>Bringing Them Home proposed ways to help these mostly</b> <b>\u201chalf-caste\u201d people, inspiring the observance \u201cNational Sorry Day.\u201d An official 2007 apology to these people and their descendants was made by then-Prime Minister (*)</b> Kevin Rudd. For the point, name these people who were raised to act white after being abducted from their half-aboriginal or aboriginal families by white Australians.", "answer": "<b> Stolen Generation</b>s [or<b> Stolen Child</b>ren; prompt on half-castes before read; do not accept or prompt on \u201caborigines\u201d or \u201caboriginal Australians\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>These people were crushed at the Battle of Mount Olympus by Gnaeus Manlius Vulso, who allied with Pergamum to subdue them for aiding Antiochus III of the Seleucids. The</b> <b>Via (+)</b> <b>Domitia was built after these people were pushed from the area surrounding</b> <b>Masilla, which was renamed Narbonensis. A leader of these people won at Gergovia before being defeated at (*) </b> Alesia; that man, Vercingetorix, was described in a set of Commentaries by a man who would later cross the Rubicon. For the point, name these barbarians who fought Julius Caesar in what is modern France.", "answer": "<b> Gaul</b>s (or<b> Gallic</b> people; accept<b> Galatians</b>; prompt on<b> Celt</b>s)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>A military force created by this action captured Joseph Hutchings in its first fighting at Kemp\u2019s Landing. At least one thousand people responded to this action, including Harry,</b> <b>a slave owned by George Washington; those people formed the Ethiopian (+)</b> <b>Regiment.</b> <b>This action, offered by the last Royal Governor of Virginia, included a declaration of martial law, and applied to (*)</b> slaves owned by rebels but not those owned by Loyalists. For the point, name this document that promised freedom to slaves who were able to reach British lines and fight against the colonists in the American Revolution, named for the Earl who issued it in 1775.", "answer": "Lord<b> Dunmore\u2019s Proclamation</b> (accept Lord<b> Dunmore\u2019s Emancipation Proclamation</b>, but do not accept or prompt on Emancipation Proclamation alone)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>One cause of this conflict was the Policy of Standardisation. This conflict included massacres at Gonagala and the Kent and Dollar Farms. During this conflict, \u201cCaptain</b> <b>Miller\u201d bombed an army camp as part of a suicide bombing force called the (+)</b> <b>\u201cBlack</b> <b>Tigers.\u201d This conflict started when a unit with call sign Four Four Bravo was ambushed by insurgents. The Temple of (*) </b> Tooth was bombed during this conflict, which included the assassination of Rajiv Gandhi. For the point, name this conflict in which the Tamil Tigers rebelled against the government of an island nation.", "answer": "<b> Sri Lankan Civil</b> War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Both this city\u2019s \u201cfather\u201d and \u201cmother,\u201d Julia Tuttle, hail from Cleveland. A year after the Meyer-Kiser Building was built in this city, it nearly toppled over in a massive storm. This city was incorporated in 1896 and named for a river, not the owner of its Royal (+) </b> <b>Palm Hotel, railroad magnate Henry Flagler. Chicago Mayor Anton Cermak was fatally wounded here by (*) </b> anarchist Giuseppe Zangara, who was targeting Franklin Roosevelt. For the point, name this city devastated by a 1926 hurricane and once home to Florida\u2019s largest building, the Dade County Courthouse.", "answer": "<b> Miami</b> (do not accept<b> Miami</b> Beach)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man reportedly used his gold watch and cigarette case to bribe Lieutenant Jack Wheelis. This man was shot in the leg during a coup attempt and subsequently developed</b> <b>a (+)</b> <b>morphine addiction, which placed him temporarily in an asylum. After sending a</b> <b>telegram saying he would take power from his superior, he was dismissed from the party and replaced in his leader\u2019s will with Karl (*) </b> Donitz. This first Plenipotentiary of Hitler\u2019s Four Year Plan killed himself with cyanide before he could be executed at Nuremberg. For the point, name this Nazi who lost prestige after the Battle of Britain, a loss for his Luftwaffe.", "answer": "Hermann<b> Goering</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>The power and influence of this system was restricted by the New Laws, which limited grants to a maximum of two generations. This system was established with the Laws of Burgos. Bartolome de las Casas argued for the (+) abolition of this system in the Valladolid Debate. The</b><em><b> repartimiento</b></em><b> system was intended as a replacement for this policy, which gave owners a number of (*)</b> natives who worked the land in exchange for being converted to Christianity. For the point, name this system to control natives in colonial Spanish America.", "answer": "<b> encomienda</b> system", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>This coach once told Governor Jim Hunt that \u201cyou\u2019re a murderer and I\u2019m a murderer.\u201dAfter this coach\u2019s team won a conference title game by holding onto the ball for about</b> <b>seven minutes in his patented \u201cfour (+)</b> <b>corners offense,\u201d a shot clock was introduced the</b> <b>following season. He won a national championship when Michigan player Chris Webber called a timeout he did not have. This coach was heavily recruited to run as a Democrat against Senator (*)</b> Jesse Helms in 1990. This man was the college coach of Michael Jordan. For the point, name this man who won 879 games as the University of North Carolina men\u2019s basketball coach.", "answer": "Dean<b> Smith</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b>Four hundred years after the fall of Rozafa Castle, this country\u2019s liberation movement gained traction after a victory at Deciq. The Assembly of Vlore granted independence to</b> <b>this country, which was formerly a vilayet. The battle of (+)</b> <b>Kruja was fought in this</b> <b>country by the League of Lezhe, which was opposed by Mehmed II and Murad II. Venice assisted this modern country in fighting for its independence from the Ottoman Empire during the 15th century. (*) </b> Skanderbeg led troops for, for the point, what Balkan nation on the coast of the Adriatic Sea near Corfu?", "answer": "<b> Albania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "He won a key free speech decision in a 1988 Supreme Court case involving his offensive (*) </b>parody of conservative minister Jerry Falwell. For the point, name this president of the company that publishes the pornographic magazine<em> Hustler</em>.", "answer": "Larry<b> Flynt</b> Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>In the aftermath of this event, a surge in poachers led to the passage of the Black Act, which made \u201cbeing found in disguise in a forest\u201d a capital crime. John Aislabie was tried and convicted for his role in this event. The subject of this event was granted a (+) 30-year-long</b><em><b> asiento</b></em><b> and was supposed to assume British debt after the War of the Spanish Succession, but ended up causing the financial (*)</b> ruin of hundreds of thousands of investors. For the point, name this 1720 economic bubble, after which an English overseas trading company collapsed.", "answer": "<b> South Sea</b> Bubble", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This group\u2019s leader Papequanaehen led it during the Esopus Wars. David Williamson killed 96 Christian members of this group in the Gnadenhutten Massacre. Tamanend, another member of this tribe, entered into an agreement immortalized in a painting by (+) Benjamin West. A 1626 letter by Pieter Schage doesn\u2019t mention this tribe by name, but notes that 60 guilders were paid in a transaction that this tribe carried out with Peter (*) </b>Minuit. Manhattan Island was sold by, for the point, what native tribe of Delaware that signed a treaty with William Penn, allowing him to create the Pennsylvania colony?", "answer": "Lenni<b> Lenape</b> tribe (accept<b> Delaware</b> before mentioned; accept<b> Esopus</b> before mentioned; prompt on Algonquin; do not accept or prompt on Iroquois)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>The documentary</b><em><b> The Plot Against Harold Wilson</b></em><b> alleges an aborted 1970\u2019s coup by the military would have replaced Wilson as Prime Minister with this man, who died on</b> <b>the same day of the Warrenpoint ambush. His wife, (+)</b> <b>Edwina, was widely suspected of</b> <b>having an affair with Jawaharlal Nehru, and his most famous position changed to that of governor-general in August (*)</b> 1947, following a successful independence movement. For the point, name this uncle of Prince Philip, the final Viceroy of India, who was killed in 1979 when his fishing boat was blown up by the IRA.", "answer": "Louis<b> Mountbatten</b> (or Lord<b> Mountbatten</b>; or Earl<b> Mountbatten</b> of Burma; or Prince <b>Louis of Battenberg</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>This man commissioned the</b><em><b> Plain Words on Agriculture</b></em><b> and disseminated the Cheugugi, the first known rain gauge, throughout his kingdom. This leader\u2019s father assaulted pirates in (+) Aso Bay during the Oei invasion as part of a conflict that he ended with the Treaty of Gyehae. This king implemented the Hall of Worthies, which produced a replacement to (*)</b> Hanja that only has 28 letters. For the point, name this ruler who presided over the creation of the Hangul alphabet and ruled for over three decades in Joseon-era Korea.", "answer": "<b> Sejong</b> the Great (or<b> Yi Do</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Marshal Poniatowski\u2019s attempt to turn the enemy\u2019s left flank in this battle was barred by Tuchkov\u2019s division. Anatole Kuragin has a leg amputated after this battle, where (+) Andrei Bolkonsky commands a regiment and is mortally wounded by a cannonball. Pierre Bezhukov spends most of this battle in a battery at the (*) </b> Raevsky Redoubt, and Mikhael Kutusov is described as being inactive during it. For the point, name this battle during Napol\u00b4eon\u2019s 1812 invasion of Russia, fought outside of Moscow and depicted in Tolstoy\u2019s<em> War and Peace</em>.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Borodino</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This author wrote a treatise whose first three books discuss human truths and whose fourth discusses divine truth; that work by this author was legendarily intended to address</b> <b>the \u201cErrors of the (+)</b> <b>Infidels\u201d on the order of Raymond of Penafort. This man wrote</b> <b>an important commentary on the</b><em><b> Sentences</b></em><b> of Lombard, whom he called \u201cthe Master\u201d in another work that discusses the (*) </b> <em>quinque viae</em>, or five proofs of the existence of God. For the point, name this Doctor of the Catholic Church whose theological writings include<em> Summa contra Gentiles</em> and<em> Summa Theologica</em>.", "answer": "Saint Thomas<b> Aquinas</b> (or Tomasso<b> d\u2019Aquino</b>)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b>A predella outside of this building depicts the inside of an artist\u2019s studio. Verrochio\u2019s </b><em><b>Christ and St. Thomas</b></em><b> replaced a hollow bronze sculpture of St. Louis of Toulouse on</b> <b>this building. This building was originally used for grain (+)</b> <b>storage, and its interior</b> <b>holds an icon of the Madonna and Child in Orcagna\u2019s tabernacle. The Armourer\u2019s Guild commissioned a statue of St. George on this building, where one statue depicts a group of men killed by (*)</b> Diocletian. Nanni di Banco\u2019s<em> Four Crowned Saints</em> and Donatello\u2019s<em> St. Mark</em> are on, for the point, what Florentine church, which is surrounded by fourteen niches and statues?", "answer": "<b> Orsanmichele</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Probably as revenge for discussing this event, Silas Soule was murdered a few months later. Its instigator had previously fought with John Slough at the Battle of Glorieta Pass. Shortly after this event took place, George Bent and his brother fought the Battle of</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Julesburg alongside a band of Dog Soldiers out of revenge. In 2014, Governor John</b> <b>Hickenlooper formally apologized for this event, which took place in modern-day Kiowa County and was carried out by the soldiers of John (*) </b> Chivington, despite the flag of peace flown by Black Kettle. For the point, name this November 29, 1864, incident where a Colorado militia massacred a Cheyenne and Arapaho village.", "answer": "<b> Sand Creek massacre</b> (or equivalents; accept<b> Chivington massacre</b> before his name is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>The Scuola Grande Tedeschi is located in one of these places, which was established by Leonardo Loredan and abolished by Napol\u00b4eon in 1797. One of these in Paris was located</b> <b>in Le Marais, and the original one of these places in (+)</b> <b>Venice was built around an</b> <b>old foundry, which gives its name to these places. Willy Brandt spontaneously knelt at a memorial to victims of an event in one of these places, which saw action by the (*)</b> ZZW and the ZOB. Jurgen Stroop suppressed that uprising, which resisted deportation to Treblinka from Warsaw. For the point, name these city areas to which minorities, often Jews, were restricted.", "answer": "(Jewish)<b> ghetto</b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>One prefect of this region, Claude \u00b4Erignac, was assassinated by Yvan Colonna after he joined a group affiliated with the FLNC. Edmond Simeoni occupied a cave in this region</b> <b>in the Al\u00b4eria incident. Simeone\u2019s son (+)</b> <b>Gilles was elected as president of this region\u2019s</b> <b>executive council in a victory for his nationalist coalition in 2015. This region briefly existed as a republic after gaining its independence from (*) </b> Genoa under the leadership of Pasquale Paoli, who would later fight against this region\u2019s annexation by France. Napol\u00b4eon was born on, for the point, what island due south of Genoa with capital at Ajaccio?", "answer": "<b> Corsica</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>One ruler of this empire was crowned in utero and had his crown placed on his mother\u2019s womb. Emperor Gaozong of the Tang Dynasty granted asylum to Peroz, a prince from this empire whose royal standard was the Derafsh Kavriani. The (+) Rashidun Caliphate sacked this empire\u2019s capital Ctesiphon. Artabanus V was defeated by Ardashir I of this empire at the Battle of Hormozdgan. Under (*) </b> Khosrau I, this empire signed the Eternal Peace with Byzantine Emperor Justinian I. For the point, name this empire in modern day Iran that succeeded the Parthians.", "answer": "<b> Sassanid</b> (or<b> Sassanian</b>) Empire", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This title, traditionally conferred with the Earldom of Chester, was not held during the reign of George VI. One ship bearing this name is the second of two</b><em><b> Queen Elizabeth</b></em><b>-class aircraft carriers, and another ship of this name was, with the HMS (+)</b><em><b> Repulse</b></em><b>, one of the first capital ships sunk by aircraft. The first holder of this title in its modern use was the future Edward II, who took it from its last independent holder, (*) </b> Owain Glendowyr. For the point, name this title, currently held by Prince Charles and given to the heir-apparent of the United Kingdom.", "answer": "<b> Prince of Wales</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Marty Balin was knocked unconscious during this event. Alan Passaro was acquitted of a murder that took place at this event; Passaro was a member of a group that had received</b> <b>$500 in free (+)</b> <b>beer in exchange for providing security for this event. Santana opened</b> <b>this event, where the Hells Angels guarded the stage from a crowd of 300,000 and Meredith Hunter was stabbed to death. The documentary (*)</b><em> Gimme Shelter</em> depicts, for the point, what free concert held at a northern California speedway in December 1969, where a violent Rolling Stones concert marked the metaphorical and literal \u201cend of the 1960s?\u201d", "answer": "<b> Altamont</b> concert (accept equivalents)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "For the point, name this ancient Greek problem which attempted to enlarge a certain three-dimensional figure.", "answer": "<b> doubling</b> the (volume of a)<b> cube</b> (accept<b> duplicating</b> the<b> cube</b>, accept the<b> Delian problem </b>before \u201cDelos\u201d is read)", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {"question": "<b>This thinker used the Marxist term \u201clumpenproletariat\u201d to describe people who were not involved in industrial production. This thinker used psychoanalysis to explain that Black people appropriate the culture of their colonizers because of their feelings of</b> <b>inadequacy. Sartre wrote that killing a (+)</b> <b>European is like \u201ckilling two birds with one</b> <b>stone\u201d in an introduction to one of this thinker\u2019s works. This thinker spent the end of his life as a psychiatrist in (*) </b> Algeria, supporting independence from France. For the point, name this anti-colonialist author of<em> Black Skin, White Masks</em> and<em> The Wretched of the Earth</em>.", "answer": "Frantz<b> Fanon</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {"question": "<b>During one campaign, forces under this man took the noses of their enemies resulting in the creation of the \u201cEar Mound.\u201d One invasion by this man was ended by the Council of Five Elders who had taken control of his territory. Forces under this man lost the Battle</b> <b>of (+)</b> <b>Hansan Island due to the \u201ccrane formation\u201d during one invasion, and that invasion</b> <b>Hansan Island due to the \u201ccrane formation\u201d during one invasion, and that invasion</b> <b>later ended after this man\u2019s forces were defeated at (*)</b> <b>later ended after this man\u2019s forces were defeated at (*)</b> Noryang by Yi Sun-sin. For the point, name this constructor of Osaka Castle who ordered several invasions of Korea and whose death allowed the ascension of Tokugawa Ieyasu.", "answer": "<b> Toyotomi</b> Hideyoshi", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>William Huskisson was distracted shaking this man\u2019s hand and thus became the world\u2019s first railway casualty after getting hit by a train. This man\u2019s residence at Apsley House was attacked by a mob furious at his lack of support for the (+) Reform Bill. He fought a duel with the Earl of Winchilsea at Battersea Fields when the latter accused him of supporting\u201cPopery.\u201d Due to his deafness, this man\u2019s shouting of (*)</b> \u201cWho? Who?\u201d created a nickname for the first Derby ministry. This man legendarily noted one of his great successes was \u201cwon on the playing-fields of Eton\u201d. For the point, name this Conservative Prime Minister who also won the Battle of Waterloo.", "answer": "Arthur<b> Wellesley</b> (or the Duke of<b> Wellington</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>One general in this war mockingly taunted his retreating soldiers by yelling \u201cRun, run, the bogeyman is coming!\u201d During this war, a battleship ran aground on Cape Three Forks and could not be salvaged. During this war, the losing side captured supplies in the Disaster of (+) Annual. Francisco Franco served as a commander of the Tercio de Extranjeros during this war, in which Hugo Stoltzenberg supplied one side in this war with (*) </b> mustard gas, which broke the will of troops led by Abd el-Krim. For the point, name this colonial war between Spain and tribes of the namesake mountainous Moroccan region.", "answer": "<b> Rif</b> War (or War of<b> Melilla</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This author of (+)</b> <em><b>Falling Man</b></em><b> denied that he was trying to \u201cfurnish factual</b>", "answer": "<b>s\u201d to a presidential assassination in his fictionalized biography of Lee Harvey Oswald. He described the fictional drug Dylar and an (*)</b> \u201cairborne toxic event\u201d in a book about Professor of Hitler Studies Jack Gladney. For the point, name this American author of<em> Libra</em> and<em> White Noise</em>. ANSWER: Don<b> DeLillo</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "<b>After picking up a rifle with a bayonet on it, this man told a reporter \u201che\u2019d put it up his butt and see how effective it was.\u201d After Paul Vallus ran for Governor of this man\u2019s state, this man hired Arne (+) Duncan as CEO of his city\u2019s school district. As mayor, this man oversaw the controversial Hired Trucks Scandal and the demolition of Meigs Field, an airport near the (*)</b> Adler Planetarium. This man developed tourist attractions like Millennium Park and Navy Pier during his six terms in office. For the point, name this politician who, with his father, combined for 43 years as mayors of Chicago.", "answer": "Richard<b> M</b>ichael<b> Daley</b> (prompt on Daley; do not accept Daley Jr., but accept any other reference to \u201cthe<b> younger</b> of the two Richard<b> Daley</b>s; do not accept Richard J. Daley)", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}